PEIZHAO LI

Name pronounced as 'Pay-Jow Lee' +1 (781)-392-5571 | peizhaoli@brandeis.edu | peizhaoli.com Volen 109, Brandeis University, 415 South Street, Waltham, MA 02454

EDUCATION

Brandeis University, Waltham, Massachusetts, United States

08/2019 - Expected 05/2024

Doctor of Philosophy-Ph.D., Computer Science

Advisor: Professor Hongfu Liu

Beihang University, Beijing, China

09/2015 - 06/2019

Bachelor of Science, Electronic and Information Engineering

Advisor: Professor Xiantong Zhen

RESEARCH SUMMARY

Academic Research: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning with particular interests in Trustworthy and Responsible AI, Machine Learning Fairness, and relevant learning/data-centric methods to detect and mitigate bias in machine learning and deep learning applications.

Industry Research: Deep Learning, Multimodal Learning (Vision + Language), and Computer Vision with applications in user attention modeling, document analysis, object detection and tracking with automotive radar and RGB camera images, automatic code editing, and keypoints detection.

RESEARCH AND INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Amazon Alexa AI

09/2023 - 11/2023

Applied Scientist Intern, Manager: Dr. Xiaohu (Derek) Liu

Bellevue, Washington

· Conducted research on language data augmentation with Large Language Models.

Google Research

05/2023 - 08/2023

Research Intern, Host: Dr. Junfeng He

Mountain View, California

- · Conducted research on user attention and feedback modeling on visual content.
- · Built multimodal foundation models for saliency, scanpath, and aesthetics score predictions.
- · Achieved leading performance on several saliency and scanpath prediction benchmarks.
- · Contributed to the collection of the first dataset on user gaze with rating.

Harvard University

01/2023 - 05/2023

Research Fellow, Host: Professor Yiling Chen

Cambridge, Massachusetts

- · Conducted research on information elicitation and peer prediction with machine learning.
- · Related multitask peer prediction from mechanism design field with multimodal contrastive learning.

Mitsubishi Electric Research Laboratories

05/2022 - 11/2022

Research Intern, Host: Dr. Pu (Perry) Wang

Cambridge, Massachusetts

- · Conducted research on object recognition with multi-view radar frequency imaging.
- · Proposed a deep learning framework for object segmentation using horizontal and vertical radar images.
- · Contributed to an in-door radar dataset collection using internal radar devices.

Mitsubishi Electric Research Laboratories

Research Intern, Host: Dr. Pu (Perry) Wang

05/2021 - 08/2021

Cambridge, Massachusetts (Remote)

- · Conducted research on object recognition in automonous driving using automotive radar.
- · Proposed a temporal information-enhanced radar object detection and multi-object tracking framework.
- · Authored and successfully submitted a research paper that was accepted at CVPR 2022.

NEC Laboratories America

02/2021 - 05/2021

Research Intern, Mentor: Dr. Xuchao Zhang

Princeton, New Jersey (Remote)

- · Conducted research on automatic and few-shot computer source code editing.
- · Proposed a method for learning from few code snippets, and performed well in code refactoring.
- · Authored and successfully submitted a research paper that was accepted at ICLRW 2022.

Adobe Research 05/2020 - 11/2020

Research Intern, Primary Mentor: Dr. Jiuxiang Gu

College Park, Maryland (Remote)

- · Conducted research on document representation learning, entity recognition, and document classification.
- · Proposed a multimodal pre-training framework and performed well on various downstream tasks.
- · Authored and successfully submitted a research paper that was accepted at CVPR 2021.

Beihang University 09/2017 - 03/2019

Undergraduate Research Assistant, Advisor: Professor Xiantong Zhen

Beijing, China

- · Conducted research on computer vision applications including facial keypoint detection and object tracking.
- · Authored and prepared three research papers accepted at WACV 2019 and ICIP 2019.
- \cdot Worked on video object detection and tracking to improve a railway surveillance system.

PUBLICATIONS

Publications in several research fields including Machine Learning Fairness, Multimodal Learning (Vision + Language), and Computer Vision, etc.

Citations: 396, h-index: 10, i10-index: 10, by Google Scholar, 09/06/2023.

Conference Publications

- [C1]. **Peizhao Li**, Ethan Xia, Hongfu Liu. Learning Antidote Data to Individual Unfairness. *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), 2023.
- [C2]. Anshuman Chhabra, Peizhao Li, Prasant Mohapatra, Hongfu Liu. Robust Fair Clustering: A Novel Fairness Attack and Defense Framework. International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.
- [C3]. Zizhang Chen, **Peizhao Li**, Hongfu Liu, Pengyu Hong. Characterizing the Influence of Graph Elements. International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.
- [C4]. **Peizhao Li**, Hongfu Liu. Achieving Fairness at No Utility Cost via Data Reweighing with Influence. *International Conference on Machine Learning* (ICML), 2022.
- [C5]. Peizhao Li, Xuchao Zhang, Ziyu Yao, Wei Cheng, Haifeng Chen, Hongfu Liu. Code Editing from Few Exemplars by Adaptive Multi-Extent Composition. *International Conference of Learning Representations* Deep Learning For Code Workshop (ICLRW), 2022.
- [C6]. Peizhao Li, Pu Wang, Karl Berntorp, Hongfu Liu. Exploiting Temporal Relations on Radar Perception for Autonomous Driving. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022.
- [C7]. Hanyu Song, Peizhao Li, Hongfu Liu. Deep Clustering-based Fair Outlier Detection. ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2021.

- [C8]. Peizhao Li, Jiuxiang Gu, Jason kuen, Vlad Morariu, Handong Zhao, Rajiv Jain, Varun Manjunatha, Hongfu Liu. SelfDoc: Self-Supervised Document Representation Learning. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- [C9]. Peizhao Li, Yifei Wang, Han Zhao, Pengyu Hong, Hongfu Liu. Dyadic Fairness: Exploring and Mitigating Bias in Graph Connections. In Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- [C10]. **Peizhao Li**, Han Zhao, Hongfu Liu. Deep Fair Clustering for Visual Learning. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020.
- [C11]. **Peizhao Li**, Yanjing Li, Xiaolong Jiang, Xiantong Zhen. Two-Stream Multi-Task Network for Fashion Recognition. *In Proceeding of IEEE International Conference on Image Processing* (ICIP), 2019.
- [C12]. **Peizhao Li***, Anran Zhang*, Lei Yue, Xiantong Zhen, Xianbin Cao. Multi-Scale Aggregation Network for Direct Face Alignment. *In Proceeding of IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision* (WACV), 2019. (* equal contribution)
- [C13]. Xiaolong Jiang, Peizhao Li, Xiantong Zhen, Xianbin Cao. Model-Free Tracking with Deep Appearance and Motion Features Integration. In Proceeding of IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2019.

Under Review Papers

- [U1]. Anshuman Chhabra, **Peizhao Li**, Prasant Mohapatra, Hongfu Liu. 'What Data Benefits My Classifier?' Enhancing Model Performance and Interpretability through Influence-Based Data Selection.
- [U2]. Tingwei Liu, Peizhao Li, Hongfu Liu. Dual Node and Edge Fairness-Aware Graph Partition.
- [U3]. Yuan Zhang, **Peizhao Li**, Feng Pan, Hongfu Liu, Pengyu Hong, Xiuwen Liu, Jinfeng Zhang. Applications of AlphaFold beyond Protein Structure Prediction.

Preprints

- [P1]. **Peizhao Li**, Zhengming Ding, Hongfu Liu. Mining Label Distribution Drift in Unsupervised Domain Adaptation. arXiv preprint: 2006.09565, 2020.
- [P2]. Xiaolong Jiang*, **Peizhao Li***, Yanjing Li, Xiantong Zhen, Xianbin Cao. Graph Neural Based End-to-end Data Association Framework for Online Multiple-Object Tracking. arXiv preprint:1907.05315, 2019. (* equal contribution)

OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

FairPy: A Python Library for Machine Learning Fairness

03/2023 - Now

A Python library for promoting fairness in machine learning, which includes a collection of benchmark datasets, fair algorithms, and evaluation metrics for convenient utilization.

Awesome Machine Learning Fairness: A Paper and Resource List

07/2021 - Now

A vast collection of over 250 papers, articles, and resources spanning multiple research fields and practical applications, all dedicated to the topic of machine learning fairness.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Computer Vision 01/2023 - 05/2023

Teaching Assistant, with Professor Hongfu Liu

Marketing Analytics 09/2021 - 12/2021

Teaching Assistant, with Professor Xavi Vidal-Berastain

Discrete Structures Teaching Assistant, with Professor Timothy Hickey	09/2021 - 12/2021
Computer Vision Teaching Assistant, with Professor Hongfu Liu	01/2021 - 05/2021
Advanced Topics in Graph Mining Teaching Assistant, with Professor Chuxu Zhang	09/2020 - 12/2020
Topics in Natural Language Processing Teaching Assistant, with Professor Constantine Lignos	01/2020 - 05/2020
Data Structures and the Fundamentals of Computing Teaching Assistant, with Professor Hongfu Liu	09/2020 - 12/2020

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Reviewed over 80 conference/journal manuscripts.

Conference Reviewer

- · Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022, 2023
- · International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2023
- · European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022
- · International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023
- · IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), 2022, 2023
- · ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2022, 2023
- · IJCNN at IEEE World Congress on Computational Intelligence (IJCNN), 2022
- · Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2022, 2023
- · International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2022, 2023
- · IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022, 2023
- · International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022, 2023
- · AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022, 2023, 2024
- · International Conference on Advanced Communications and Computation (INFOCOMP), 2021

Journal Reviewer

- · IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology
- · IEEE Transactions on Multimedia
- · IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence
- \cdot IEEE Computational Intelligence Magazine
- · IEEE Access
- · Machine Learning
- · Big Data
- · Neurocomputing
- · Neural Networks
- · Journal of Combinatorial Optimization
- · Journal of Electronic Imaging
- · IET Image Processing
- · IET Computer Vision

Others

· External Review Panel, Michtom School of Computer Science, Brandeis University

ACADEMIC TALKS

An Introduction to Fair Machi	ine Learning	
· Guest lecture on COSI/ECO-148B	: Introduction to Machine Learning, Brandeis University	04/2023
	Machine Learning for Business, Brandeis University	04/2023
· Guest lecture on COSI-159A: Com	puter Vision, Brandeis University	04/2023
· GSAS Computer Science Alumni C	Celebration, Brandeis University	03/2023
· MRSEC-Waltham High School Piz	za Talk Series, Waltham High School	09/2022
\cdot Brandeis Precollege Academic Imm	nersion Program, Brandeis University	03/2022
Releasing the Tradoff in Algor	ithmic Fairness	
· International Business School Ph.D	O. Seminar, Brandeis University	03/2022
· Computer Science Seminar, Brande	eis University	02/2022
Code Editing from Few Exemp	plars by Adaptive Multi-Extend Composition	
\cdot Data Science and System Security	Department, NEC Laboratories America	07/2021
Two-Stream Multi-Task Netwo	ork for Fashion Recognition	
\cdot IEEE International Conference on	Image Processing	09/2019
Multi-Scale Aggregation Netw	ork for Direct Face Alignment	
· IEEE Winter Conference on Applie	eations of Computer Vision	01/2019
MEDIA COVERAGE		
The AI Ethics Brief, Montreal AI I AWARDS	Etnics institute	
Meta Research Ph.D. Fellowship F.	inalist (83/3200+)	2023
GSAS Career Fellowship, Brandeis		2023
Dissertation Research Award, Bran		
COSI Outstanding Research Award	l, Brandeis University	2022
Library's Research Excellence Prize	e, Brandeis University	2022
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear	cch Fellowship, Brandeis University	2022 2022 2022
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration	cch Fellowship, Brandeis University	2022 2022 2022 2022
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award	cch Fellowship, Brandeis University	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis University	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award sity	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award sity eihang University	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B Competition Excellence Fellowship	Award sity eihang University eihang University	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award sity eihang University , Beihang University duate Electronics Design, Beijing	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017 2017
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B Competition Excellence Fellowship Second Prize in National Undergran	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award sity eihang University , Beihang University duate Electronics Design, Beijing	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017 2017
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B Competition Excellence Fellowship Second Prize in National Undergra Outstanding Volunteer Award, Bei	ch Fellowship, Brandeis University Award sity eihang University , Beihang University duate Electronics Design, Beijing	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017 2017
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B Competition Excellence Fellowship Second Prize in National Undergra Outstanding Volunteer Award, Bei	Award sity eihang University, Beihang University duate Electronics Design, Beijing hang University	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017 2017
Alfred Schonwalter Summer Resear ICML Complimentary Registration CVPR Travel Grant Award CVPR Virtual Registration Waiver Ph.D. Fellowship, Brandeis Univers Academic Excellence Fellowship, B Competition Excellence Fellowship Second Prize in National Undergra Outstanding Volunteer Award, Bei TECHNICAL SKILLS Programming Languages	Award sity eihang University, Beihang University duate Electronics Design, Beijing hang University Python, MATLAB, Shell script, Java, LATEX, HTML	2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 - 2023 2017 - 2018 2017 2017

Latest Update: 09/2023

Fluent in English and Mandarin

Languages